SAURABHPRAKASH

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Bengaluru, India

9686608315

saurabhprakash25@outlook.com

PROFILE SUMMARY

I'm a self-motivated and highly enthusiastic Senior Software Developer with 4 years of experience seeking a responsible career opportunity where I can use my skills to continuously contribute towards achieving the goals of the organization, while at the same time ensuring self-growth and enhancement of my skill set

PROFESSIONAL SKILL

C++ Design Thinking Git Object Oriented Design

Unit Testing Debugging Mentoring OODB

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Development Engineer

April, 2021 - Present

Tally Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

- Owning a module that would enable the history of transactions to be maintained along with the capability to interact data with 3rd party data
- Made significant contributions in improving the speed of the overall database system by implementing partial read and write optimization

Software Development Engineer - II

April, 2020 - March, 2021

Tally Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

- Did the system design, code design, implementation and component testing of an entire component based on hub & spoke model used for exchanging data over a distributed lan.
- Created a diagnostic tool used across the organization
- Developed a sub-module used by other modules for exchanging 3rd party data with GSTN

Software Development Engineer - I

July, 2018 - March, 2020

Tally Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

- Made the in-house file system (an OODB) the only component in the organization with 100% unit test coverage
- Made the file system concurrent by implementing a Range-Tree based file indexing system
- Increased the maintainability, reliability and usability of the file system by reorganizing it and removing unwanted dependencies

EDUCATION

B.E in Computer Science and Engineering

2014 - 2018

Sir M. Visvesvaraya Institute of Technology

Aggr: 78 % First Class with distinction in all the semesters

AISSCE 2012- 2014

Bijendra Public School Percentage : 89 %

AWARDS

Super Coder 2021 – 2022

Given to one person in the entire engineering function for demonstrating:

- Well thought-out code design and code
- Zero (or near zero) defects in outcome
- Non-functional aspects covered well
- Demonstrates elegance in code

Rookie of the Year 2019 – 2020

Given to one person with less than 2 years of experience from the entire engineering function for :

- Showing exceptional outcome and dedication in gaining mastery over the area of work
- Demonstrating ability to solve complex problems independently
- Putting in extra effort in completing a critical part of the work

Turficate of appreciation

2019 - 2020

For showing commitment throughout the year in organizing different employee engagement programs

OTHER ACTIVITIES

- Gave C++, Data Structures and Algorithms training to the batch of 2020.Created a diagnostic tool used across the organization
- Mentored a Software Engineering Intern on creating a OODB with proper file indexes in C++
- Currently mentoring 3 Software Engineering Interns on creating a standalone application that can communicate with WhatsApp
- Being a member of the employee-engagement group, organized multiple programs for the organization including the annual football league.